so how how are you how are things you
know All Things Considered I am okay
yeah to make structure out of no
structure you know find mediums and
vices and things to do with my time I
feel fulfilling yeah yeah
I'm doing well I feel kinda about the
same way yeah um you know but I have
kids so nice I have three kids so ho
question question for you before we have
is this a conversation are we hanging
out or we like interviewing like you as
a person - yeah um well I'm totally okay
with that I'm totally just okay with
kind of doing it as a conversation
that's kind of how I approach my
interviews anyways you're just kind of
chillin and they're just generally
trying to get to know the other person
and awesome just hanging out so it's
great to be on the same page yeah which
is great cuz I don't know a whole hell
of a lot about you anyways cool that
works out perfectly
yeah I feel so yeah awesome so where are
you where do you live right now I'm in
Pittsfield Massachusetts which is I
usually live in Brooklyn I grew up about
40 minutes north of New York City and
Westchester County um but my grandma
lives up here and she is you know a
house in the mountains and for this time
of year it's just like so beautiful so
me and my partner Rebecca we are up here
and yes that's where we've been for like
nine weeks now nice that would be a
great place to be his in the mountain
sweet feeling grateful for that for sure
if my husband and I talk about uh you
know when the kids get a little older
and we kind of do our thing we
definitely want a house in the mountains
for sure yeah where are you where are
you right now
Buffalo New York well why
20 minutes outside Buffalo New York and
in the suburbs of sweet low but yeah
yeah homeless people
definitely definitely we've run in the
same kind of Buffalo music scene circles
so absolutely it's been very cool to
watch them essentially I saw them play
in a friend's backyard really not that
long ago I know and I think about it and
just to see the success that they've had
is been very cool you know and of course
from here one of the guys maybe actually
two of the guys live I live in North
Tonawanda and two of the guys I think
actually like live in this same like
little town so it's to have people in
your like same community especially
because I live in a very Republican
demographic okay area say that as as
lately as I can I don't try to get super
political on my show or anything but
right I'm sure you understand so it's
nice to have those kind of people to
come from here too so sure
happy happy to dive into whatever
[Laughter]
wanting to keep your content no please
focus yeah but I have shared uh we we
hung a giant rainbow peace sign flag in
in our front window in response to my
across the street neighbors Trump 2020
flag so that's just kind of how I make
my political statement no yeah that's
just that's great that you're showing up
in that way it's I you know yeah it's
interesting to a bet if interesting to
live in a community that has different
perspectives like across the street like
that
my partner's brother and his wife just
came to visit us actually they're in
Boston and they just moved into a new
spot and they have a similar situation
going on we're like one neighbor is
hanging a trump plug and then there the
neighbor next to that has a black lives
matter flag and
you know it's just interesting to think
about it is very interesting that you
have all these people that are living so
closely together and you know how so
different their political views are but
I use it as a teaching moment with my
kids I have a 16 year old I had him when
I was 19 Wow
so yeah that was an experience yeah and
we have completely different views on a
lot of things but we are able to come
together and talk and you know have
really insightful conversations and I
think it's great because it's helped him
like not be a douche yeah it's a
challenging thing to help hold the space
for the conversation with somebody you
don't necessarily agree with mm-hmm and
that's the I think that's the problem
that's the issue is there's people on
both sides that that aren't listening
and they're just shouting over each
other and I think that is the biggest
thing that we can do is to just learn
how to listen to each other yeah
compassion
I'm down for compassion sure sure world
overview love kind of stuff yeah
absolutely that's how I feel so you're
talking about you're at your grandma's
to talk about your family my family my
dad's from Boston my mom is from Long
Island yeah what else can I say about
them I have a younger brother he's two
years older than me he is he is
currently working as a paralegal
managing clerk kind of assistant at a
law firm right now in downtown Manhattan
with goals and aspirations of heading to
law school eventually it's a pretty
suburban upbringing that I had like I
said I grew up like 40 40 minutes
outside city in a town called Chappaqua
yeah I had a very fortunate
and I you know lived a pretty suburban
northeast life I guess you know whatever
that means eventually I was super into
sports for most of my childhood and then
had a pretty serious set of injuries
playing soccer in high school the way my
bones are structured and my lower half
of my body are not built to sustain the
type of impact and wear and tear that
the running and conditioning soccer
requires so through pushing through pain
and just wanting to keep playing I
eventually developed stress fractures in
both of my hips geez you know I wasn't
down to accept that it was real pain I
thought it was just the pain to push
through right going kept going basically
until the point that I couldn't walk oh
that's kind of like what I point to as a
big pivot point for me towards a more
artistic musical passion I had I'd been
playing guitar since six or seventh
grade but when I was completely you know
removed from athletics and I couldn't
involve myself there you know that's
when I discovered Logic Pro on my laptop
and really diving into writing music and
understanding music production and you
know a couple of my friends who were
more into music and playing guitar and
whatnot we're really making strides and
they're in their musicianship which I
wasn't necessarily finding myself called
to so I like was the one who bought the
mixer and a couple mics and we record
you know I was like the engineer kind of
thing so eventually I guess the question
was been my family but they were super
supportive about you know throughout
this journey and eventually decided to
pursue music production for college
that's what brought me out to Michigan
yeah that's nice yeah
nice so you said you started playing
guitar what like what inspired you to
pick up guitar and not drums or keyboard
or something else in pretty typical
fashion my dad is like you know into a
lot of classic rock I would say so you
know from around fifth or sixth grade
for a couple years him and I and
sometimes my mom or sometimes a friend
or dad or whatever would you know hit
these classic rock concerts so like the
who mess Square Garden and ac/dc and Ben
Halen like those kind of bands yeah you
know guitar players are the ones that
are featured in those bands like the
legend and honestly Angus Young is as
much of a front person frontman and
ac/dc as any singer so that was kind of
what drew me to guitar playing actually
yeah yeah so that's that's why I was
drawn to guitar playing I would say hey
thanks yeah of course and being a little
kid and you go into the shows and it'd
be like hell yeah yeah so like my dudes
growing up for like slashed and Eddie
Van Halen and Angus Young that was one
of those into in like a middle school in
high school yeah that makes sense my
five-year-old is he's my little um freak
it's so funny he's been to 15 shows I
think he's a five and he goes everywhere
with us and it's funny because I talked
about him obviously all the time on the
show and stuff and my husband who is
more like the behind-the-scenes kind of
person he will go and like take him to
the bathroom or whatever and people will
be like Brendan and my husband's like
who is this dude right now
and he'd just think about like what he's
like soaking in music-wise you know
because he watches it and pays attention
and we just got him his first drum set
for Christmas and okay so is he
she's into it okay yeah he's into it so
that's the loved one it is the loud one
it's funny my husband bought drum set
for him and a pair of noise cancelling
headphones for me
so cancel each other out he's a smart
man he knows oh yeah trying to do my
podcast thing and he's just raging in
the other room so awesome nice for sure
so you went to school in Michigan
correct yeah I ended up studying audio
engineering almost audio engineering in
Michigan and I wanted to really be into
the studio recording side of things you
know like setting up microphones and
mixing and being a producer in that kind
of environment but you know like big
studio and big studio projects don't
have as much they're not as widespread
I guess now in the music industry and I
quickly learned that lesson at school
and I luckily the program that I was a
part of at Michigan the performing arts
technology program wasn't just purely
audio engineering
it was also incorporating ideas of
coding and visual arts and like how can
we find the intersections between a lot
of different mediums artistically so
that's kind of where an openness and
interest in the visual realm and how to
like you know make musicality and
artistry out of different types of
things
aka lights you know that's kind of like
where it it goes so in college yeah my
freshman year in sophomore year was kind
of like the time where I was in - um
freeze like actually in Tom freeze as a
fan I was developing an interest in
lights and obviously seeing Humphries
was like the light shows pretty proud
part of the um for his experience so I
ended up buying a cheap set of lights
with the bands that I was working for
working with okay just like my best
friends at
just hanging out with ya we would play
the house party shows and bring you know
our kind of shitty light setup and set
off the fire alarms with bad smoke
machines that was the kind of thing and
mostly just tried to continue to figure
out what what it means to be a lighting
designer or what it means to do lights
and yeah it was it was a pretty
extracurricular journey with with
influences from what was going on in my
class environments I would say that's
pretty cool yeah so you talked about
getting like in Dumfries so when was
your first show my first show I don't
know date anymore it's it's January 2012
okay yeah that's how I am too I'm like I
give you the month in the year it's hard
it's my junior year of high school they
were playing in Manhattan at the Best
Buy Theater they're Nikon theater okay
it changes names all the time yeah one
of those venues yeah and I you know I
actually was not into jam bands at that
time one of my close friends who was
kind of like my guitar player like best
friends and also the dude who I was
recording his music like that's this is
this friend he was into jam bands and
I'm fries McGee and Humphreys McGee had
come up in conversation before and I saw
that one of my favorite bands was
opening for him freeze and at the time
that was the London souls I don't know
if you've heard that name yeah yeah
that's super familiar but I've heard of
them yeah I haven't seen much from them
in the last few years which is
unfortunate but they're like power trio
rock fuzz awesome Led Zeppelin cream
sounding thing it's like just awesome
vibes anyway they're opening it you know
made sense for that to be a concert for
us to go to so we went and then I stuck
we stuck around
obviously for Humphries after the
opening slot and it was really awesome
confusing and awesome but you know I was
like junior year of high school still
being able to control myself as far as
smoking weed so like I saw like I saw
the opening at mostly sober and then
like we lit a joint so it was cool but
also like didn't really understand what
was going on and then a year after that
saw them at the Beacon Theatre and was
like more into it and then by the time I
got to college in the Midwest they were
like playing close you know two nights
in Detroit and in two nights in
Cleveland and two nights in Wisconsin
just like all these drivable places
mm-hmm and found a community and some
homies in college who were down to you
know like be into it and that way I met
some people through like the Michigan
I'm freeze University of Michigan / ann
arbor scene thing who are into jam bands
yeah and so that's where I kind of like
got into it that's cool so how many
shows have you seen as as a fan I guess
we could say no yeah I mean it was those
first like two or three years of being
into it as a fan that I was like going
for it and seeing it nights in a row by
my junior and senior year so that's 2015
and 2016 ish I would like only see that
and when they came to the Detroit film
war I didn't have it in me to like
travel anymore so I would say like 20
maybe 15 15 20 times and then pretty
fast after graduating school I was
working for Spafford so that doesn't
really count as seeing them as a fan cuz
like I'd run them to that helene they're
like we opened for them for two weeks or
something like that so I I definitely
have shows on my belt right I was also
working in the industry you're like
summer camp festival whatever Fanfan not
working let's call it 20 nice nice well
I mean that'sthat's pretty good and in
the time that you got into them and then
when you started like getting into it
actually doing stuff so when did you do
did you do lights just at summer camp
for you were working with Spafford
correct yeah I did lights for one of the
production companies that supplies gear
for the okay and fire stage yeah got in
touch with those people through so my
co-workers at an internship I was doing
in Chicago and they were awesome and
super down for me to be around and help
out in any way and at that point I
really didn't have much technicality
around lighting I did around audio but
not around lighting but I expressed that
I was interested in lighting that's how
I learned yeah summer yes so the summer
camp 2016 I was working as the house of
thee on the campfire stage it was also
just like working a major festival that
was also semi hosted by my favorite band
it was yeah an awesome experience had
some I started dancing goes like really
serious names come on to that saves like
dough pod and and playing ping-pong like
all those kind of like semi semi big jam
bands for playing on that stage that
weekend so I got to meet they're
traveling out these which was a really
big learning experience for me
and specifically meeting Luke Stratton
from dope thug
slash all the other wild things he does
now was awesome to meet him in person
and Manny from pigeons I ran into Manny
like six seven months ago at who lean
this past year and in his phone I'm
still he's lighting designer for pigeons
by the way mm-hmm it's phone solicitous
and campfire staged which is just that
is funny that's you know he come all
this way I'm not a fire station it's
always good to like remember that though
that is it's so cool that you were just
like I don't really know what I'm doing
but I'm really interested and I'm
willing to try and exactly I mean why
not I mean that's how I have been with
the show like I started my show and I
seriously knew nothing about
podcasting I knew nothing about anything
except for um freeze McGee like that was
it when you start seeing the bend it was
2000 May 2007 they played a free show
here in Buffalo they used to have this
thing called Thursday in the square and
they would have like the best bands come
like Mall came and unfreeze came I think
they came like twice actually John
Butler was here I mean so many people
and it was free like it was just in
downtown Buffalo and it was free and it
was the day after my friend's 21st
birthday
and I mean of course we celebrated her
21st birthday yes so the next day she
didn't feel like going and I'm like well
I'm still going I still want to check
these guys out and yeah we went I went
with some other friends we had a great
time but I didn't was it like an
immediate clique for you were you like
that was that was it or you took a
little effort it took a little bit it
definitely did I I went to I didn't see
them again for a whole year until them
following summer camp so summer camp
2008 I saw them and in that year time me
and my best friend had really gotten
into mo nice so we saw Lakes just so
much mo but of course being from Buffalo
you know me it's the same sort of thing
there's so many drivable places that we
could go and so just a ton of Mo and so
we went to Motown and then we went to
summer camp in 2008 and so then when we
were there like I experienced um freeze
on a different level
absolutely so then there for me it just
kind of like moved and you know it it's
there's been times in my life where it's
just more intense than others obviously
being a mom mom but it definitely always
been something that's you know like a
piece of me since then so I mean the
Internet
makes it really easy to stay in touch
though I mean mm-hmm the time that I was
super into it as well when I couldn't
necessarily be at shows there were live
streams and also you know internet
threads on like how to hear what's going
on and reading set lists and listening
to the shows you know there's there's
there a ways to stay into it which I'm
so I mean a grateful especially now for
being an embrace McGee fan and all the
things that we get even right now but
just anyways you know the shows on Dougs
the next day or sometimes even that
night you know like just to be able to
listen to the music that quickly and
it's just very fortunate for that sure
that's a shout-out opportunity - Chris -
Chris Mitchell that audio engineer sure
for sure sometimes you're like damn yeah
I mean it's you know it's it's a machine
the touring side of this organization is
just locked in absolutely locked in so
it's been a great experience to work
alongside professionals of the caliber
of these guys I bet I bet I mean and
I've said that to Sam he's been on the
show twice and I've talked to him about
that how they're just a mate like
amazing and that's from my point of view
you know as the fan so you know for you
to say that is the co-workers and I
equate it to to being parents you know
the people behind the scenes that are
making everything still function yeah
you know and and it's just it's amazing
yeah it takes a lot of passion because
there are numerous angles and aspects of
the road lifestyle that are not ideal
but at the end of the day if there's an
underlying commitment and passion to
like what live music is bringing you
know that's kind of where it's stemming
from I would say yeah yeah that's
I mean I feel like that's probably the
same for anything in in the arts
especially if you're gonna pursue it as
as a job you know there's gonna be parts
of it that are just not very beautiful
at all you know that it's the passion
that pushes you to to keep going yeah
absolutely
it's it's an interesting time to think
about like the place of art in the world
right now as like live music is
completely pause right there's none of
that is going on right now so it's
definitely a reflecting time to think
about what that really means in America
I don't know I don't know it's been an
interesting experience for me coming out
of like college and trying to like
really think about big world concepts
and understand my place in the world and
art is really I you know there's a lot
of idealism and passion and love in art
and then like there's also the realities
and challenges of making it function in
a society like that's just it's
complicated stuff yes but it's been I
think also interesting the I mean I
obviously already knew the role that it
played in my life but especially at a
time like this when people what do they
need they need books or music or movies
or whatever it is it's different mediums
of art whatever it is yes and how
actually important all of that is to
humans like as we're surviving basically
right now and doing whatever it is
that's going on um how interesting it is
that that's kind of been pointed out to
some people that maybe didn't really
before yeah yeah I hope we all you know
whatever real reopening or you know
reintroducing a safe a safe society like
what we bring to the table as far as our
like priorities and care for art really
looks like once coronavirus is more
under control you know that's uh I'm
interested
see the way that turns out yeah my bad
so tell me about like applying for the
job
so waffle like they make this
announcement is that is that how you
find out just like everybody else you
find out at the same time that waffles
taken a leave yeah I mean there's the
public announcement which is like you
know that makes it official
and on that day friends who are in the
industry or who are just friends of mine
who are not necessarily obviously like
reach out to let me know and I'm like
yeah dude I [ __ ] know like I see thank
you but I don't it's come up as an ass
but it was just like yeah dude I know at
the time I was still with Spafford but
for reasons very unrelated to
Jefferson's leaving about fries was just
like reevaluating my place it's Baffert
and making a transition moving into a
new apartment in Brooklyn and finding
new places in the city to like really
dig into so like I was already making
movement to depart from the
organization's backward so then once
that actually became official you know
that was just another thing on my plate
to like really start to consider as the
forward movement so the first place that
I went to try and reach out was to Bob
Bob stone who is the proxy manager from
fries he he and I met the year before in
the summer of 2018 when Spafford open
front forum freeze for like three weeks
I was only one of two crew members on
that tour with Stafford it was just me
and at the time was the front house
engineer his name was Chris Erickson who
was also like long long long time
friends with a lot of the members of
Dumfries community because he's a
Chicago guy specifically Bob so reaching
out to Bob I knew that I had like the
connection
and mutual friend of Chris and who was
like a very trusted person of Bob's he
was like Chris was like my reference to
Bob basically okay so I sent him like a
very official cover letter listing out
the reasons why I would you know be a
very legitimate and right candidate for
the job and I was like in a coffee shop
with my partner Rebecca just like all
nervous like wow what what is there lose
by said clicking sin but I was like you
know right reading every sentence
checking all the punctuation all the
grammar making sure it's good and then
finally I'm like ah [ __ ] all right click
it you know and then fast after like
within the hour he responds that like
hey great to hear from you how'd it
feeling that you would reach out
actually the best thing that you can do
moving forward for the application
process is to put a few songs into a 3d
rendering and show us like what you
would do if you were designing for I'm
freeze Mickey and actually over the past
couple of months I've been sending
Dumfries guys and they've posted posted
them some of those 3d digital renderings
that I'm that I'm talking about I was
actually asking you about those yeah
yeah yeah so basically embedded in the
lighting console that I use is called
the grand ma - it's like you know
industry standard they actually just
released grand MA 3 so this is a good
learning time to start to understand the
new the new technology but it's not
quite there anyway within ma - there's
also visualizer built in so it's a
really powerful tool because there's no
actual limit to what you can put in a
computer so if you want to as we saw if
like the shine on you crazy diamond
thing like if you want to make an
enormous rig with a bunch of circles and
make it in giant stadium you can do that
it's like it's a computer yeah so I did
a waste more scaled-down realistic
version of that for my application so I
designed a rig that was like pretty
different from Jefferson's
and it went over really well like really
really well a lot of the applications
that they saw looked very similar to
what waffle is doing which is obviously
not really what they're looking for and
transition time they wanted to like
change and use it as a really gross
point so the part that stuck out to Bob
eventually to some of the band members
was I was utilizing groups of odd
fixtures like so Jefferson was all about
the even symmetry whereas I'm not
necessarily that way so given that my
application looked different then
basically everyone else's they're like
great okay on to the next next round
essentially because I mean they made a
public announcement that was happening
and also yeah so given that it was
public they got I can't even imagine
probably thousands oh yeah I was gonna
ask if you knew I I would have to
imagine it's in the thousands at least
but that's probably to Kevin
that's probably to the general band I
think it's like I don't know if some
email that's probably on the website
like contact Humphreys or whatever right
um but I went straight to Bob so I was
definitely like a good in the door part
that I had going for me so the next step
after I had gotten you know past the
digital round was to actually meet the
people and on the crew I shouldn't be
having the band members at this next
part that I'm about to talk about but
they were coming through Huntington New
York which is on Long Island so that's
like my area they're on tour and I just
like came out to the show around
dinnertime had dinner with Bob and Bobby
and like heard about a lot of the
logistics about of the job and this is
how it goes here and it says you know
what the deal is and I met some of the
other crew members I didn't know and
just like got a feel for what you know
what it's like to be in my organization
and obviously they also started to get a
feel for who I am as a person and I was
just like a cool hangout time like I
didn't run lights or do anything
technical show is completely
when I got there it was just kind of
like a meet and greet opportunity
actually there that's a funny part of
the story there it was the hang was
going well and Bob and Bob we were like
okay cool so we wanted booked an
audition audition run with you are you
available in a couple weekends for
resonance vests and I said no which was
idiotic I had I had other plans and
wasn't like fully on my game
understanding the stakes at play so I
just said I said no I'm not available
those weekends I can try and see if on
the weekends and they were like they
didn't say to my face but behind the
scenes they were just like dude what
dude just said no to an offer like Barry
I told and I next day I'm like talking
to my people about how wet and I'm like
can't actually offered it but I wasn't
around unfortunately and everyone's like
you idiot let them know that you cancel
everything you need to make that happen
so that email Bob like not even 24 hours
after meeting them being okay by the way
I cleared cleared my calendar and it was
too late
they had already booked someone else to
do that I was like [ __ ] that sucks
luckily I've stayed persistent and
pretty active with like hey following up
can we make a different run of shows
work what's going on and I did I got the
Georgia theatre / who mean run and that
was my live audition we're actually gots
like meet the band and rip some shows
and see how you know it would really
feel yeah I just want to make sure that
late was kind that's kind of yeah that's
that was the audition went really well
at that point it was I think it was
basically just down to me and Luke who
did the next two weekends so that was a
painful experience because I went first
and so like I was watching Luke do the
awesome like Halloween run at the anthem
with like the coolest way you know it's
a great lighting rig there mm-hmm so
stressful man and it was just a waiting
game at that point it was you know the
audition run went really well I made
good friends with both Ben and crew and
is a good hang and then I had to leave
and they had to have another guy come in
audition so it was like yeah like good
hangs like good to see you but also
maybe talk to you in a couple weeks also
maybe not like we'll see so I was like a
weird challenging dynamic there and like
yeah during the next few weeks I was
like do I reach out like Louie Louie is
our lighting crew chief and we get along
really well and we got along really well
during those two weeks and I I just
wanted to like reach out and say hi but
given the fact that they were
auditioning someone else I didn't even
feel like I could you know yeah step off
so eventually two or three weeks after
Luke was all done and thought or
Humphries was done they said they would
make a decision pretty soon and then the
way it went as far as finding out I got
the job of course like Kevin texted me
in some weird cryptic way where he was
like hey are you around to chat today
that was all he said like [ __ ] I was
like I'm actually not a running him on
the way to a gig right now and he's like
cool it's not time pressing we'll just
talk tomorrow
and that's all he said and I was like
wait about a half-hour call my dad I was
like this is what it is I don't think
it's a good sign because it's like if
it's not time pressing and he's not you
know like that doesn't feel great so
then on the subway to my gig and I was
in New York at home about 45 minutes
later I was like you know what whatever
I'm just gonna text him back and die
what's the deal like all right like to a
half it or not so I was like what are we
talk I think I texted him like what are
we talking about tomorrow and he's like
many answers I was like sitting there's
can't even look at my phone waiting for
it to vibrate
like with an answer and the answer was
like where we are asking you if you are
interested in taking the job of lighting
designer for us it was like sick sick so
they have to do this like full day
really tedious and not enjoyable
corporate gig in New York but I was you
know with good news made the day way
easier ya know as that was kind of how
it went and then celebrations on just my
end because it wasn't necessarily public
and then the day that they announced it
on the internet was super cool it just
very oddly happens that today they
announced it
Munya n-- are you familiar with Munya
n-- a little bit I know some veterans
there there Jim then who I worked with
before Stafford who are also very close
friends of mine they happened to be
touring through New York City that day
so like I met up with them in the
morning walked around New York City with
friends who I hadn't seen and way too
long had a great day I'm freeze made an
announcement and then obviously excuse
me my phone it starts blowing up you
know with congratulations and then that
night tool was playing in Brooklyn I
went to see tool alone which was my plan
and it always but like just go and see
that band has is just such a personal
experience and yeah well so I awesome
day of walking around city with old
friends and an awesome announcement it's
going on I capped the day off by going
to see tool and like perfect seats right
behind for a house just totally taking
in the experience and like what the [ __ ]
was going on in my life and that's how
it went
yeah that's kind of like the whole thing
that's very cool crazy six seven months
yeah I bet that's that's pretty pretty
incredible that's awesome so your first
so your first run with them is then New
Year's right officially yeah
okay that's right person okay
new years correct okay so like how do
you how do you feel like now you get the
job so you're like it's got to feel
different now you're not trying out you
don't have that anxiety so now you go
into New Year's how are you how do you
feeling yeah New Year's was way more
grounded and calm I actually flew out to
Chicago a couple weeks before New Year's
to go do some prep work at our shop our
gear shop ecto productions which is just
outside of Chicago they're right by
O'Hare they supply all of our gear for
tour and some of the gear for New Year's
shows so we did like the the X bars that
were on the ground for New Year's like
we did some work as to like what's the
best way to hang this and yeah just prep
work basically so getting to work with
Louie and work with the guys who work it
out though and start to feel more
comfortable was a really good a couple
days for me just starts to get the
wheels move in and then New Year's yeah
New Year's of course my plane my flight
is delayed I land in Denver too late I
show up to load out late hello excuse me
load in late also for some reason didn't
eat when I got off the plane so I'm like
desperately hungry in the altitude
episode and for New Year's but luckily
you know it's Oh New Year's was cool
because we got an extra day to load in
so we loaded all the lights in before
the first show but the whole day before
so we had an entire day just to tweak
and make sure everything was good to go
on a lighting front so I was like
someone coming into a new gig that was
awesome oh I'm sure for sure give
yourself a little buffer and exactly
normal day we're loading in at 10:00
a.m. and needs to be basically ready but
a 1:00 p.m. dish which is like three
hours to build the entire show but for a
bigger show at New Year's to get the
full extra day awesome for sure sure
via news was I don't really I don't like
to use the word nervous with dog free
shows because it's like I don't
necessarily feel nervous but there's
just a lot of energy
an adrenaline you know a lot of
excitement yeah for sure yeah yeah the
size of rig that the the budget we get
from New Year's was definitely the
biggest budget I had had to date as far
as making a design from scratch and
there was a there was an interesting
challenge with the film were in Denver
cuz the ceilings really low mm-hmm
mm-hmm so a lot of ideas for lighting
rigs of that size would usually
translate to a room that's bigger like
I'm saying the amount of budget we have
allotted and like the size of show we're
going for at new years usually fits into
a space that's bigger than the film or
strike an interesting challenge and
decision making point as far as how do i
balance where to put lights and what
lights to put where when the ceiling
height is so low and in hindsight it was
a learning experience I think there are
a few things that I would like to try
differently when or if we do go back to
the film arc because given the low trim
low ceiling height in Denver and yeah
and as we continue to do that were you
at the new your shows not this year okay
no I wasn't so we did four we did four
shows and there were actually three
small subtle iterations of the rig like
night one of the bar is where in X's and
then the next night they were more like
diamonds and then we move the diamonds
out further and further again for the
fourth night so that was just like again
points to the fact that it was learning
experience and it's all about
Federation's and it's a process to find
what actually feels appropriate and like
you know like what I want to I don't
think there is a final form of like what
the lighting rig or lighting design for
I'm afraid we'll be moving forward it's
just a continuous process well it's it
just the same with their music you know
I mean I feel like you could only have a
lighting
be consistent like that if you're
lighting a show that is consistent like
true you know like a band that just
plays the same setlist every night every
night is so different so you cannot
expect it to be the same way with that
at all yeah absolutely taking that fact
into account you know definitely plays
into the into the design process because
like okay so I'm freeze has a set of has
a wildly enormous range of songs that
they're gonna play and also within those
songs there's enormous sections of
improvisation so challenge with
designing for them is how do I make a
lighting rig like morph and move and
feel fresh throughout all these
different fresh musical sections yeah so
it's got to keep you on your toes though
- totally
you know I I'd be curious yeah I'd be
curious what a smaller um freeze tour
would look like if they skip not
necessarily played the same step every
night but like Scout really focused and
scaled their set down cuz I mean at
least for me that would make a different
design process like okay we're gonna do
this sort of certain vibe most nights or
something like that that would that
would lend opportunity to make some
decisions that were really catered
towards like okay there's gonna be a
really heavily Jake Sinan girl like solo
section highlighted spot a lot of the
time maybe then I would take into
account like okay is there a way that we
can make the lighting rig like focus on
Jake that certain way but given that the
band members are you know very heavily
featured throughout the night and it's a
lot of group improvisation how do we
make the lighting rig represent that
that's kind of a challenge right so how
do you then get so right before when our
tour starts I guess winter tour is kind
of where you guys left it off it wasn't
quite spring yet sure how do you get
ready for tour so you have new years and
I'm sure you maybe have like a little
bit of time off and then
and weeks yeah okay and then you start
Winterthur so what is Winterthur look
like getting ready professionally and
personally totally nice
technically Winterthur as far as gear
and design work goes and programming
work was mostly ready actually before
New Year's when I went back to Chicago
in middle of December that that was
where a lot of the decisions were made
and actually the the New Year's rig was
basically just an expanded version of
what the winter tour rig would be okay
so from a technical standpoint it was
pretty ready to go in those two weeks in
between New Year's and winter tour you
know a lot of my programming can be done
remotely wherever I am on my computer so
you know I continued to workshop and
improve the technical stuff that like
you don't necessarily like you will see
it as an audience member but you won't
necessarily like realize what the
changes are from show to show of like
what's going on in the programming so
that's mostly what I was working on in
between those in between that time and
then personally and emotionally yeah
what is the prep look like on that front
you know it's definitely spending time
at home and and figuring out and
planning what does life look like for
the next four four or five weeks given
that there are this block of tour dates
here and also off time here and just
trying to make it a make life make sense
moving moving forward I guess I'm not
necess I was not necessarily a stranger
to tour life heading into this because
of my time with Munya and Spafford so
from that angle that was good to have at
least somewhat of a reference point to
what it feels like to be touring and
with um freeze all things consider
especially within the jam band scene the
touring scale is actually it's pretty
manageable I mean it's it's definitely a
lot of weekends but it's weekends as
opposed to being on a tour bus for
literally three months at a time that
doesn't really happen right now with the
way they structured their tours so from
that angle you know pretty grateful for
what the job presents right having that
schedule because of them having families
and stuff they have really structured
this amazing tour schedule where they're
able to still kind of have their family
life and tour life and so it's
definitely a good time in their in their
lives for you to come on board where
before they were playing 250 shows a
year so crazy [ __ ] so I completely
acknowledge the fact that the
challenging grueling grind as far as
touring goes from fries I was not you
know in the van for that like the van
days that was obviously like you know
before my time so definitely grateful
for the fact that I'm joining during a
from certain angles easier time on the
body and mind and soul and stuff like
that
absolutely so talk about lighting the
caverns like that was that was one of my
highlights I was there I did the caverns
and then both nights in Nashville know
especially my last blast
I'm freeze run um which it was amazing
like we took my five-year-old with us
and we're in this cave and which I'm
still it was just such like an
interesting experience like it was
you're kind of like looking around like
okay we're in an actual cave right now
thank you
it was kind of like a mindfuck but the
moment that you just lit up the room
yeah in the triple wide and you know
they just kind of like the whole
beginning of the song obviously anybody
listening knows what I'm talking about
and then just when it just goes right
into it and you lit up the whole cave
sure the
look on my kid's face was just like holy
[ __ ] and I'm looking at him like this is
amazing because he's experiencing this
but I'm experiencing this with him and
Wow yeah that was amazing and when I
listened back to that show you can hear
the audience like the audience
collectively had this same feeling that
he did in that moment like yeah
absolutely
I mean what it was that like for you
yeah burns was a long challenging and
also incredibly rewarding day for me I
mean there's only one in and out so only
one place to go in and out and you can't
actually fit the semi truck down there
so it was this very long and tedious
process of pulling a few pieces of gear
off the truck and onto these like two
small tractor trailer is that the right
term I don't know
just like small trailers and driving it
down the driveway into the cave I'm like
we have an entire semi-truck of gear so
that is a long process on the most ideal
of days our truck like pulls up right
into the dock and we can push everything
straight onto stage or if not a short
push from truck to stage anyway that is
not what's going on the caverns so
that's one challenge but the biggest
challenge which ended up being like the
whole thing of the day is the space is
so on ideal I guess from just a standard
production angle so like the stage is
slanted in multiple ways
there is no flat anywhere on the stage
this kind of like bumpy rock thing
there's a freaking moat around the back
of the stage yeah
running water behind the band the whole
entire time so basically we had to from
a lighting standpoint it was like oh and
there's no place to hang lights in the
air and there's no place to hang lights
over the crowd - like for front light
like at the band so it's this entire
challenge of like we have designed this
rig for a certain set of circumstances
and now all of that's out the window so
what are you gonna do so basically the
way that kind of day
I walk in and survey what's going on
like what are we gonna do and we ended
up repurposing most of our gear to do
things that it hadn't been doing for
most of the tour so those bars those
like led long bars that we had been
using new years and for tour actually
ended up putting them on the ground and
only facing them back at the rocks at
the cave so they're purely functioning
as just throwing color on the space
which was really effective because the
whole experience was about being in the
cave so to then throw like awesome
psychedelic crazy colors at the already
crazy psychedelic space was just it was
awesome it was awesome yeah so that so
the day was kind of just like placing
lights in this dirty gritty space and
making sure it wasn't in water or gonna
fall over or like all this stuff and you
know the idea of symmetry just like
throw it out the window like get over it
because it's not gonna be perfect so
like make the design and make the
placement of the lights more catered
towards the experience as opposed to
like a camera shot that's from perfect
Center and get the perfect angle that's
like not the goal when you're walking
into the cave and it worked out really
well like we put just like this entire
stack of lights on the side just to
light the band that was super out of the
way so you could still experience the
band and the cave but also see the band
was it worked out great and yeah they
open with triple wide which is like you
know has the samples you know I'm not
going full force during that intro drum
sample but then there's the drop where
the whole band actually comes in and
then yes it's rippin time okay get all
the beams and the circles and the colors
going
I love to remind me in the cave because
it's just like strobe mania and I've
seen some videos from remind me in the
cave and it's just like we use really
bright lights powerful fixtures and the
space it was just like perfect
perfectly balanced room to spit room
room / space to lighting power balance
cuz like it just perfectly lit off the
entire space from front to back like no
matter what was going on you could feel
the awesomeness of the cave at all times
so when you're doing like a crazy strobe
e dark section remind me it felt like we
were in like that scene in Star Wars
where they're driving the Millennium
Falcon and they like swerve into the
asteroid belt and park to escape from
there the people that are chasing them
and it turns out it's like actually the
mouth of a worm that's that's a great
analogy I'm such a Star Wars nerd so I'm
all like oh I can't wait to see where
he's going with this
it was that scene for like the entire
cave the sheriff is shaking because we
were actually inside of the worm yeah
that's so great we found like the best
spot cuz we were up my son loves to be
up front so well like we had he's got
like great headphones and take him up
front for a little bit yeah and then we
wound up coming like out and we found a
spot of the cave that was like this flat
seated spot and it was like directly
across from where you were and the
people at the venue were like just don't
stand on there and you can sit and we
sat there the whole show and it was
great because we had this amazing view
of just yeah everything it was it's the
way you painted that cave was just it
was beautiful I am glad to hear it yeah
it was it was a challenging day and a
long day and given the fact that it was
gonna be really not ideal and everything
was gonna be out of place you know that
was it was it was tough but once the
show started and it looked you know it
started we started to understand the
gravity and awesomeness of what the
opportunity was smooth sailing from
there is a great time I think everybody
really enjoyed it yeah it was awesome
and then a huge contrast to what you're
doing the next night in Asheville now
you're in this arena and
I personally I said that too because we
did the next two nights and we walk into
the arena and Asheville and I'm like I
said to my husband I'm like this is
weird like seeing them first of all in
an arena I'd never seen them in a space
that big anyway it's sweet but then of
course going from the caverns to this
arena it was so weird so now you have
more room so talk about like how like
different that was for you yeah so a day
like Asheville is where we get to build
letting rig the exact way that it was
drawn up and planned to be because when
you walk into the Asheville arena it's a
blank grid there's no lighting rig in
house there's no infrastructure there
it's just we are bringing all of our
gear to put in the exact places that we
wanted to originally put them so from
that angle it makes the load in and
build pretty smooth and then yeah I mean
they sold a lot of tickets so I know
that the first few times they played in
Asheville they had the stage like right
in the middle and they would cut off
half of the arena okay you being wise
okay but since they sold so well this
year I know that they moved the stage
back so it made the space even bigger
and even more awesome so it was just
like a lot of yeah there was a lot of
room to do really pre things in the air
and point awesome shapes at the back
wall because there's a so much space
between lighting rig and back wall so
yeah from that angle it was it was
awesome Asheville actually ended up
having a couple not know not a couple
just yeah two - pretty hilarious
technical difficulties I don't know if
you ended up noticing that it's yeah we
noticed one might you have to know I've
talked to some people who claim they
didn't notice and I was like dude were
you even watching cuz like it was a
pretty bad eye I noticed it but then my
husband like
tapped me on the shoulder and noticed
you not panicking but like obviously
like trying to fix and things and he's
so basically yeah for those listening or
watching or whatever who didn't see what
happened right at the end of eat which
is like this dark evil demonic metal
song the data line between my console
and the lighting rig went out no when
that happens unfortunately you know I
I'm sure there's a certain way that we
can program it's just like go to a
neutral scene if that happens but right
now what happens when our data goes out
is it just stays where it last was and
of course the moment that the data went
out was like literally full-on strop
every light full strobe so the song eat
ends and the entire rig is so strobing
with silence and it was like out of a
nightmare man cuz like you can slowly
start to hear the audience like in
Guitar Hero when you start to fail and
you can hear like the oh no boo that was
like real life happening people were
like oh [ __ ] like the lights are
literally strobing in my face and
there's no music going on obviously when
that happens I'm like on the radio
trying to figure out what's going on
things were smooth sailing at that point
so Louie our crew chief actually had
gone to get dinner because he was like
okay everything's cool but then all of a
sudden the radio is going off like it's
freaking ah so that sucked and I know I
mean guys are professionals and they've
been there a million times with
technical difficulties so Brendon like
literally continues the show and the
banter as if nothing is happening as if
the lights aren't strobing which is like
good on him the bands have talkback mics
so to talk to each other and I can hear
them that's for like cues and and improv
improv stuff you know I talk to each
other as to make decisions that only
they can hear anyway in while that was
all happening Joel goes and sits
back mic and it's like nice lights bro
trying yes we eventually figured it out
that obviously rattles me for the rest
of the set because it's like now I'm
like haphazardly trying to do things
because I'm nervous the whole thing is
just gonna go out again we eventually
figured out the problem or so we thought
and then second set starts and they're
opening with dark brush yet yeah dark
brows which again it's like a heavy
awesome tune and right as the set starts
the whole thing goes out again
fortunately it was on a more neutral
seen not even neutrally everything was
off again I don't know if you really did
you realize that was happening at the
show yeah yeah that means you were
actually exhibit but like you know
they're playing awesome dark brush and I
had no control of the rig for like the
first two minutes of the song so there
were literally just no lights for the
first two minutes oh man yeah that was
like I think the highest take account
they've ever done anywhere period and
that's how it goes that is exactly how
it goes that's like the live music thing
you know it's it's life though like it's
the same thing I feel like every time
I'm ready to like jump on a call with
somebody or do something for the show
like all of a sudden something happens
like right before with my kids or my
knee it couldn't happen yesterday when
there was nothing going on or exactly
why couldn't this have happened at any
other show or at any other moment but
full strobe why but it was cool and like
I said everyone has been there a million
times they're such a professional
touring organization they've done way
worse
technical difficulties than that
throughout the years so like it wasn't
even enough conversation necessarily
with anyone it was like okay cool move
on you're all good cool great yeah I'm
good have a good second set well it's
good for you I mean you're gonna have to
do those kind of things and the only way
you're gonna learn is in the moment like
doing
and having to figure it out and you
didn't panic that's that's what my dad
always used to tell me you didn't you
didn't really panic so you're good yeah
yeah I was I was panicking a little bit
inside I don't know what I looked like
I'm sure I looked moderately packed
we'll see but I was like kinda just
crouching down trying to unplug and
replug some things and eventually a
workaround was fixed so what what do you
what are you gonna do just not going
yeah okay that's kind of the story of
Asheville and caverns that was that
weekend yeah yeah so like you guys are
gonna get ready to go to California and
play your shows in March mm-hmm and so
like what what happens like you're are
you already there - I know like pretty
much everybody was there like you know
they call it the day of - God chose for
Thursday Friday Saturday and Sunday that
week that was the San Diego la San Fran
and then Sunday at Terrapin a pretty big
run corona bias was definitely a thing
in the United States at that point like
very much being talked about in the
media and understood as a real threat
but no one really knew how it would
impact right away or if it would at all
to our shows so we all everyone on the
crew flew into the LA on Wednesday night
and we woke up on Thursday to the news
that the entire thing was canceled so
like as a long 24 hours I flew into LA
had dinner fell asleep and then flew
back the next day and for New York you
know cross-country flight that's a fun
well yeah wow that was kind of wet it
was stressful but also you know given
that I mean I definitely had had um
started to understand that coronavirus
was serious and things were gonna be
dangerous or possibly canceled it was
almost a bit of a relief just to have
like a decision because it was so like
is it gonna be careful is it not is this
gonna happen is it not just to like see
and see a decision made and at least
know what
was going on in the short-term was
relieving but now we've reached the you
know the nebulous ambiguous I really
know what we're that's how I felt about
Iceland because my husband and I were
gonna go to Iceland and I just started
to feel a lot of anxiety about all of it
and then of course I mean cuz then we're
watching not only what's going on here
but then what's happening in Iceland
Verger and I started to get concerned
again being a mom of three like are we
gonna get quarantined in another country
for six months or that yeah that would
suck it was like this whole thing and
when they finally cancelled their you
know postponed it I was I it was the
same feeling you're just like yeah just
make the decision thank God I don't have
to make this decision and then just feel
like I regretted not going absolutely no
hundred percent thank you for doing this
for me yeah yeah I think yeah all the
responsible decisions were made in a
timely appropriate manner I think all
things considered I yeah reflecting on
it the way I'm freeze handled it as far
as trying to make the things happen that
we all wanted to happen but also
prioritizing safety and responsibility
you know yeah I think those handled
pretty well by team team um absolutely
especially um for something that has
never had to be handled before who the
hell has ever had to cancel an entire
tour or international dates because of a
pandemic like who in the hell ever
would've thought that that I mean maybe
something as a movie but so here we are
in uncharted territory yeah that that's
how I feel is like every day is like a
movie almost like some weird Will Smith
movie or something I don't know yeah not
anything
like Fresh Prince of bel-air do you
think I am legend I saw in the movie
fears I did too and my dad but I was
yeah I'm the um yeah I'm younger than a
lot of the guys on the Humphries team
and often times like their references go
way over my head or like when I talk
about a shared experience and like tell
them how old I was at the time they're
like oh my god are you kidding me anyway
I was still pretty young and not very
into horror movies and I remember seeing
it and walking out in the middle because
I was too scared same I was like no no
so you didn't did you ever see the full
movie I did okay I mean it gets worse
because then the dog dies and stuff and
you're like oh this is the worst
definitely art Reggie that's funny I've
never heard anybody else say that so
that's great I'll admit it - it's
[ __ ] up art that's funny
this has been fantastic it's been great
getting to talk to you and get to know
you a little bit I was like well I want
to get to know him anyway he's new to
the fam I mean that really new because
you've been doing this for a little bit
but yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah I'm
hopefully you know re-entrance into
whatever life we we you know to evolve
to and hopefully that includes a lot of
unfreezing again touring and I would
imagine that people are you know finding
and missing the experience of live music
they're you know it's up and down you
know cuz like sometimes I'm I'm
definitely finding great habits right
now and using the time to reflect and
and progress and figure cool I've been
trying to do like more yoga and
meditate and eat better and like a lot
of things for sure and also you know re
reconsider things and whatnot and yeah
hopefully we can come back with more
perspective and more compassion and like
rocket even harder yeah well that's what
at that's what I think I think what this
time is meant to be for on a bigger
level is it's time for us as humans to
get closer to self and kind of evaluate
the relationships in our lives and you
know obviously being here with my
husband and my three kids every day it's
not perfect hmm
but again we've taken those moments as
teachable moments and you know my
marriage with my husband has certainly
been much stronger through this you know
you have to build a team in a different
way yeah I mean absolutely that's that's
how we're we're taking it because yeah
you know there's definitely still days
where I want to wring his neck but
that's human that's being partnered with
someone but it's it has it's helped
build our team stronger and helped me
connect with my kids more and it's
important to take this time to do that I
think yeah I'm coming with the world -
really absolutely I've been able to
connect with my friends more yeah
actually you know I'm more intentional
about texting people and and reaching
out to people and with actual like
meaning you know you're like
legitimately like hey how are you really
like how's things going on it's not just
like mm-hmm not going through the
motions am i right right and I think
that's important yeah yeah definitely a
challenging time but hopefully uh
increased perspective can make it an
optimistic and time for change and
really envision and imagine you know the
more improved future yeah where I'm at
right now try and learn the ways I can
be involved in that more awesome future
yeah for sure so when you do get back
out on the road what is like your dream
room to some light up with Humphries oh
good question
I was super bummed out when Red Rocks
was canceled would that be your first
time lighting up Red Rocks as a
headliner yeah okay I've done it as an
opener twice I'm actually I'm freeze
last summer with Spafford and some
before that was bad for opening for
biscuits but that's you know a day set
with you know one-eighth of the rig and
it's you know it's awesome don't get me
wrong it's an experience but - from the
ground up designed a rig for such a
unique space is is slush was something
I'm really looking forward to like again
in a similar way to the caverns like
delegating a portion of the rig to
specifically always be lighting up the
rocks cuz like that's the whole thing of
Red Rocks and is there a way we can just
make the experience more specific and
catered towards Red Rocks that's what
I'm looking forward to I mean Iceland as
an experience and trip was going to be
awesome so I hope that some rescheduling
or something of that you know
rescheduling or half making that happen
in a different format happens Beacon
Theater was that's Jack did it cool I
think it's kind of it right now that I
can cut that comes to mind and then um
freeze is still you know rocking awesome
Festival slots locking and Bonnaroo and
all those kind of places I'm looking
forward to eventually going back to you
yeah doing the bigger stage at summer
camp probably - totally yeah summer camp
summer camp is again an awesome
opportunity because it's a festival but
humphreys basically hosts it on that
stage so the design lighting wise is
mine so that's an awesome project cuz
it's like yeah do your thing me but do
your thing but also consider the fact
that this is a shared stage for four
days of music so like that's yeah I was
again was and are looking for is I am
looking forward to summer camp for sure
because the way I get to design and
share the rig with so many awesome
touring lighting designers who come
through yeah I bet are you gonna check
out the summer camp stuff they're doing
this weekend yeah for sure yeah III
haven't looked at the exact schedule yet
but given that summer camp was supposed
to be happening and I miss it so much
I'm sure I will be celebrating or trying
to re-experience it in some way to make
it feel like I'm there yeah and that's
what we're gonna do - we're gonna
definitely check it out and have it the
way that we can have it so yeah awesome
well this is been really great yeah a
lot of fun talking to you how's how's
the fans fans bad you know coming up to
you after shows and stuff everybody yeah
yeah pretty cool yeah
it's been a very welcoming experience so
far I tend to roll my eyes when people
asked for set lists without saying words
oftentimes people from like afar well
just like wave at me and then be like
and like I'm down to give you setlist be
[Laughter]
kind of awkward I would be like okay
behind me people do that I'm usually
just like no like my autographs are like
what do you want let me have that's so
weird but also there's thousands and
thousands of people who go to the shows
and obviously there are characters and
so yes I would say it's been a great
experience so far with the fans and
community has home yeah that's awesome
very good to hear yeah we're very happy
to have you
everybody is super excited to
like to have you on board and it's just
been so awesome watching you I mean we
watch any livestream that they put on
and the shows that we've gotten to this
year and yeah and then to hear your
story of how he did this it's it's cool
that's very cool
I appreciate that I'm very very grateful
to be where I am and continue to move
where I do where I do go yeah and that
awesome well this is cool is there
anything else you wanted to talk about
that we didn't get to I don't think so
at this moment
okay cool yeah talk to you again soon
yeah absolutely be great to be on the
show anytime you always welcome to come
and hang out and chat yeah I mean now
that you have a going on zoom you know
you have the opportunity to open it up
to multiple people to could be fun to
hang out with Sam on hear me you and Sam
yeah I'm totally down we should
definitely do that I'm into it well
we'll make it happen
for sure that would be fun sounds really
good Sam's a great dude and he's been
such a huge supporter of the show like
this from the very beginning he was on
Lake episode number four and he's just
like listens to it and he just always
talks about it to people and totally
it's so cool to just have that kind of
support he's got a pretty immediately
warm presence that's pretty funny and
easy to hang out around so yeah just
good people yeah totally sure well yeah
peace and love tell people take care
this was fantastic but soon bye